specificmedia.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy | Viant

**This privacy policy was last revised on May 23, 2018.**

Viant is a digital media company comprised of a family of companies that includes the Viant and Adelphic businesses (collectively, “Viant,” “we,” or “us”). Viant is the owner of a cloud based advertising platform and provides services to publishers, advertisers and other companies (our “Clients”) that allow them to plan and execute interest-based digital media campaigns and measure the performance of those campaigns (the “Viant Services”). The Viant Services are no longer offered in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or European Union (“EU”) and we are in the process of deleting all personal information relating to EEA residents in our databases. We expect the deletion of all EEA data to be complete by the end of 2018.

This Privacy Policy (“this Policy”) describes Viant’s practices and policies for the information (sometimes referred to as “data”) we collect through our website www.viantinc.com (the “Site”) and from other sources that we make available to our Clients through the Viant Services. This Privacy Policy does not apply to Myspace or Adelphic. The privacy policy and privacy notice for Myspace is located [here](https://myspace.com/pages/privacy) and [here](https://myspace.com/pages/eeaprivacy). The privacy policy for Adelphic is located [here](http://adelphic.com/privacy-policy/).

We generally do not collect information about consumers through the Site, but we do collect other online and offline information about consumers’ interests and habits through web tracking technologies, and from our other business partners like data providers, ad exchanges, and mobile app attribution companies (our “Ad Partners”). We use that information to create audience segments that we make available to our Clients to enable them to deliver targeted, interest based advertising and to conduct analytics and research. The Viant Services deliver the targeted advertising messages to consumers (the “Users”) on computers, mobile phones and similar devices and enable us to report back to our Clients about the effectiveness of their advertising campaigns.

By partnering with us as Client, or visiting the Site and/or otherwise using the Viant Services, you agree to the terms of this Policy.

Please read this entire Privacy Policy carefully. This Policy contains links that you can click on to get further information or exercise the options you have about your information. To make this Policy more reader-friendly, we use everyday words such as use, transfer and storage to describe what we do with your personal information – but this Policy covers all of our data processing activities.

Some of the key topics you may be interested in include:

**A. Personal information you give us**

Viant generally does not collect personal information regarding individual Users through the Viant Services, and only collects personal information via the Site when it is provided to us. In most cases, if and/or when we obtain personal information, it relates to our current or prospective clients and business partners. When we say “personal information,” we mean individually identifiable information that would allow us to determine the actual identity of and/or directly contact a specific living person, such as an email address or telephone number.

We collect personal information only when we are contacted directly by an individual through the Site and the individual voluntarily provides personal information to us, such as by submitting a question or registering to use the Viant Services. To the extent we receive personal information through our Site, we use personal information only in ways compatible with the purpose for which it was collected, such as to respond to email communications or questions, to facilitate registration for and delivery of the Viant Services, or for billing purposes. By voluntarily providing us with personal information, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Policy.

##### **2\. Additional Information We Receive About You**

**A. Automatically Collected Information**

The Viant Services collect information about your device and the ads that we deliver onto your device. This information, which is collected passively using various technologies, may come from such sources as your web browser or the apps that you use. We also obtain the precise location (e.g., latitude and longitude coordinates) of your device and may use that information to assist our Clients with targeting ads tailored to your interests.

We also combine the information collected across multiple sites and mobile apps in order to create interest segments that help us target future advertisements based upon those inferred interests. This combined information may also include whether you engaged with specific content or ads; and whether you went on to visit an advertiser’s website, downloaded an advertiser’s app, purchased a product or service advertised, or took other actions. This practice is sometimes referred to as behavioral advertising or interest-based advertising.

We use this information as part of the Viant Services to perform a variety of tasks, such as limiting the number of times a specific advertisement is presented to the same User (frequency capping), providing an advertisement to only certain types of Users, or providing a report to a client on the number of its advertisements that were clicked. We share this information with Clients, Ad Partners, vendors, and other companies that we conduct business with as permitted by law.

Viant is a member of the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) and adheres to the DAA’s Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising by respecting the DAA’s consumer choice tool for you to opt out of interest-based advertising. The DAA tool is located at [https://optout.aboutads.info](https://optout.aboutads.info/). Viant is also a member of National Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and respects NAI’s consumer choice tool for you to opt out of interest-based advertising. The NAI tool is located at [https://optout.networkadvertising.org](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/). These tools enable you to opt of from receiving interest based advertising from many of our Clients and Ad Partners.

We offer an “opt-out cookie” to block the placement of Viant’s behavioral advertising cookies on your system for two years from the time you opt out. When we detect our opt-out cookie on your browser, we do not serve you with interest-based advertising on the browser or device from which you have opted-out, or on the browsers or devices that we believe are linked to your opted-out browser or device. However, if you delete your cookies or begin using a new browser or device, you will need to opt out again. Browser settings that block all cookies may prevent the opt-out from operating correctly and certain privacy software may delete the opt-out cookie or cause it to function incorrectly. Furthermore, the opt-out cookie is not effective on devices that do not accept or otherwise support cookies, such as iOS based mobile devices, internet connected televisions and other non-cookie based connected devices and applications.

You may install our opt-out cookie by clicking the button below:

**B. Cookies and other Web Technologies**

In operating the Viant Services and Site, we use a technology called “cookies,” which are small text files that our Site serves to your browser when you access the Site or that some of our Clients and Ad Partners serve to your browser when you engage with them. Our cookies collect and store audience segments, help provide additional functionality to the Viant Services and Site, and help us analyze usage more accurately.

Although most web browsers automatically accept cookies, many browsers’ settings can be set to decline cookies or alert you when a website is attempting to place a cookie on your computer. However, some of our services may not function properly if you disable cookies. We do not support the Do Not Track browser option.

We also use an advertising identifier created by your mobile operating system to store information on our servers and later retrieve it to provide the Viant Services. The Android Advertising ID and Apple iOS’ IDFA are examples of advertising identifiers. For more information about advertising identifiers, please check the settings of your mobile device.

New technologies that perform similar functions may be developed. If we adopt new technologies that are not already described in this Policy, we will update it to let you know.

You can learn more about how we use cookies and similar technologies [here](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-cookie).

**C. Log Data**

We receive information when you view content on or otherwise interact with our Services, which we refer to as “Log Data.” For example, when you visit our websites, sign into our Services, or interact with our email notifications, we may receive information about you. Log Data includes information such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, pages visited, location, your mobile carrier, device information (including device and application IDs), search terms, and cookie information. We use Log Data to operate our Services and optimize the performance of our Services.

**D. Information from Our Clients, Affiliates and Ad Partners**

Our Clients, Ad Partners, and affiliates share information with us such as browser cookie IDs, mobile device IDs, [IP address](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-ip-address), device type, operating system, [hashed](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-hashed) email address, or [hashed](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-hashed) mobile ID (e.g., Apple IDFA or Android advertising ID), as well as location-based data such as Wi-Fi, cell tower, GPS or diagnostic location information, contextual information, and demographic information including age, gender and zip code.

Information we obtain from these third parties (including our affiliates) about you may be appended to information that we otherwise have about you for the purposes of targeting advertisements. For example, we match [hashed](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-hashed) versions of mobile IDs to data that we have de-identified (made pseudonymous) about you that resides in our platform in order to target advertising to you based on your device activity, inferred interests and location information.

We use your appended data to create interest based segments, including non-sensitive health and financial related [interest-based segments](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-interest-based-segments) as part of our services, including general [interest-based segments](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-interest-based-segments) such as “Health::Medical Centers” and “Finance::Insurance,” and custom [interest-based segments](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-interest-based-segments) such as “Health::Dieting::Acai Berry” and “Health::Contact Lens.” You may click [here](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-segment-list) for a list of our general health and financial related [interest-based segments](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-interest-based-segments). We do not use [interest-based segments](http://www.viantinc.com/privacy-policy/#privacy-interest-based-segments) to determine credit worthiness or for insurance underwriting or employment eligibility purposes.

In the process of serving an advertisement to a device, we, or our partners, may decide to serve an ad based on one or more audience segments associated with that device, and the audience segment we believe may be associated with that device. Where Viant is able to use this and other information to infer that one browser or device likely belongs to the same User or household, the Viant Services may consider those browsers and devices “linked” for purposes of ad serving and interest based advertising. This linking process is sometimes referred to as creating a device graph.

When you use third-party apps, websites or other products integrated with the Viant Services, they may collect information about your activities, subject to their own terms and privacy policies. Those companies’ use of cookies and other data collection technologies are subject to their own privacy policies, and the terms of this Policy do not apply. Like many companies, we may allow cookie matching with select Clients and Ad Partners, but those parties are not authorized to access Viant cookies. Where we share information with such third parties, we only share pseudonymous information that does not include your name, email address, or contact information and we require them to follow privacy and data security principles and practices that are substantially similar to ours.

##### **3\. How We Use, Share, and Disclose Your Information**

This section describes how we share, use and disclose personal information in connection with operating the Viant Services and our Site.  We do so with your consent, because it’s necessary to operate the Viant Services or our business, or because it’s required by law.

**A. Managing Your Information**

**Opt out**

As described above, Viant uses the pseudonymous information we collect via the Viant Services and the information with combine it with from our Clients, affiliates and Ad Partners to create audience segments that are targeted to Users’ inferred interests. This information is typically associated with the advertising identifier referenced above and is used by us, our Clients and Ad Partners, including advertisers and publishers, to deliver targeted advertising. As described above, you can opt out of receiving targeted advertisements from Viant and many of our Clients and Ad Partners here, [https://optout.aboutads.info](https://optout.aboutads.info/) and [https://optout.networkadvertising.org](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

When you opt-out of interest-based advertising through the Viant Services (as described above), we stop sharing your information with our Clients and Ad Partners. That does not mean you will no longer receive advertising on the internet. However, it does mean that the display advertising you see will not be behaviorally targeted by us to your interests or preferences, so long as the opt-out cookie remains in place. Further, except for the specific restrictions noted above, our opt-out cookies do not otherwise prevent us from continuing to collect, maintain or use information as described herein, including for non-personalized advertising purposes (such as ad delivery and reporting) on your opted-out browser or device or on linked browsers and devices.

**B. Service Providers**

We share your data with our service providers, including our contractors and business partners, who we engage to help us provide and manage the Viant Services, ensure network and information security, provide a more personalized experience, and analyze usage of the Site and the Viant Services. For example, we use Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, and Yahoo Analytics to help us understand your usage of our services, and partner with Aerospike to help us manage user data. Our service providers are located in the United States and other countries and we share your personal information with them subject to obligations consistent with this Policy, impose other appropriate confidentiality and security measures, and only share your information on the condition that these third parties use your personal information only on our behalf and pursuant to our instructions. We share your information with our service providers to further our legitimate business interests of operating our business, and only do so after considering the potential impact to your individual rights.

**C. Affiliates and Change of Ownership**

We share your information within our corporate group, and particularly with our affiliates Viant Technology LLC, Viant US LLC, and Xumo LLC for uses consistent with this Policy, such as to help operate the Viant Services.

We may share, disclose, or transfer your information if Viant is involved in a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider, as permitted by law and/or contract.

**D. Non-Personal Information**

We share your non-personal information, such as aggregated information (in statistical or summary form that does not include any personal identifiers) with third parties in order operate and improve our service and conduct research about and analyze usage of the Viant Services.

**E. To Respond to Your Requests Based on Your Consent**

If you interact with us on our Site or request information from Viant, we use and/or share your information, including any personal information you provide, to respond to your inquiries. We may also use your personal information to send your updates about the Viant Services or changes to this Policy.

**F. To Protect our Legal Interests**

Additionally, we will use your personal information for other purposes permitted under this Policy, such as to protect or comply with legal rights and obligations.

There may be instances when we will use and/or disclose information we collect and receive where we have, in our discretion, a good faith belief that such use and/or disclosure is necessary in order to: (i) protect or defend our or your legal rights or property or those of our affiliates, employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements); (ii) protect the safety and security of members of the public, including responding to emergencies where there appears to be a danger of death or injury to any person; (iii) comply with the law, law enforcement, or legal process or proceedings or requests from public or government authorities; (iv) prevent fraud or other liabilities.

##### **4\. EEA Data Subject Rights**

As mentioned above, if you reside in the EEA your personal information that is in our databases is not being used by Viant or shared for any purpose other than preparing it for permanent deletion. Most of it has already been deleted and the rest will be deleted by the end of the year. Nonetheless, under the new Data Protection law we are still obligated to inform you of your rights. You may object to our processing of your data, request that our processing be restricted, review or request changes to your personal data, or request that your personal information be deleted and we erase your data by contacting us at [dpo@viantinc.com](mailto:dpo@viantinc.com).

You may also complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. Contact details for data protection authorities in the European Union are available at [ec.europa.eu](http://ec.europa.eu/).

You may exercise any of these rights free of charge. However, we may charge a reasonable fee or refuse to act on a request if the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, in particular because of its repetitive character.

Your privacy is important to us, so we may ask that you provide sufficient information to verify your identity before we respond to your requests. In some situations, we may refuse to act or impose limitations on your right if, for instance, it is likely to adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others, prejudice the execution or enforcement of the law, or interfere with pending or future litigation.  
For more information on your rights, please contact [dpo@viantinc.com](mailto:dpo@viantinc.com).

##### **5\. Children’s Information**

We do not knowingly target advertisements to children. If you believe your child has been targeted by Viant with interest based advertising, please contact us at [privacy@viantinc.com](mailto:privacy@viantinc.com) to have the data provided by and associated with your child deleted.

##### **6\. How We Secure Your Information**

Viant is committed to protecting the security of the information we collect. We use a variety of technical and organizational measures to protect information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure, both during transmission and once we receive it. We store your information on secure servers.  However, no digital transmission or form of electronic storage is completely secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

##### **7\. How Long We Keep Your Information**

We store personal information such as email address, telephone number or billing details for so long as you continue to have a business relationship with Viant and for a reasonable time thereafter for record keeping purposes. We store pseudonymous identifiers, such as cookie IDs and mobile advertising ID’s collected via our Services, for as long as our systems are able to recognize a particular User, and for 90 days thereafter.  We store log data for 90 days.

##### **8\. Cross-Border Transfer of Information**

We are a growing corporation with operations in multiple countries. We have developed data practices designed to assure information is appropriately protected. While our primary data centers are in the United States, where the laws of your country allow us to do so, you authorize us to transfer, disclose, store and use your personal data in the United States and any other country where we operate or engage service providers to assist us with our services, consistent with this Policy.

For EEA residents, please be aware that the laws of the USA and other countries outside of the EEA may not protect your data to the same level as the laws of the EEA, or give you the same rights that you would have in the EEA (including rights relating to access to personal data by law enforcement or national security/intelligence agencies).  But when we transfer your personal data outside of the EEA, if the receiving country’s data protection laws do not offer the same level of protection as the laws of the EEA, we place contractual obligations (the EU Model Clauses) on the recipients of your personal data to ensure that your personal data is adequately protected.

##### **9\. Additional Privacy Rights for California Residents**

Residents of the State of California may request a list of all third parties to which our online service has disclosed certain personal information (as defined by California law) during the preceding year for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and want such a list, please contact us at [privacy@viantinc.com](mailto:privacy@viantinc.com). For all requests, you must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you – you need to attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. Please note that we will not accept requests via telephone, mail, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

##### **10\. This Privacy Policy May Change**

Viant will maintain personal information in accordance with this Policy. If Viant decides to change this Policy, we will post the changes on this page and revise the “Last Updated” date above. Any changes to this Policy will become effective upon our posting of a revised Privacy Policy on this page. Use of the Viant Services or Site following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy that is in effect.

##### 11\. Contact Information

For questions or concerns relating to privacy, please contact us at [info@viantinc.com](mailto:info@viantinc.com).

_Data Controller_ : Viant Technology LLC

4 Park Plaza, Suite 1500

Irvine, CA 92614

_EU Representative for purposes of this policy_ : [dpo@viantinc.com](mailto:dpo@viantinc.com)

##### Key terms

  1. Cookie
  2. Embedded script
  3. Hashed
  4. Interest-based segment
  5. IP address
  6. Non-personal information
  7. Personal Information
  8. Pixels
  9. Server Logs
  10. Unique identifier
  11. User Panel
  12. Web Crawler

###### Cookie

A cookie is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. Cookies may store user preferences and other information. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some website features or services may not function properly without cookies.

###### Embedded script

An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about the way an advertisement displays on a website. The code is temporarily downloaded onto a user’s device from our web server or a third party web server, is active only while you are connected to a particular website, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

###### Hashed

Hashed means de-identified. Technically, a hashing algorithm is a function that converts a data string into an alphanumeric string output of fixed length. When we use “hashed” in this privacy policy, we mean a de-identified version of the data that is hashed. For example, the hashed version of “example@example.com” is: 23463b99b62a72f26ed677cc556c44e8.

###### Interest-based segment

A user or group of users categorized on the basis of preferences or interests inferred from the data we collect and receive that are used as a basis for displaying advertisements and other content intended to be more relevant and useful to the user or users. Examples include “AUTO::Auto In-Market MASTER,” “TRAVEL::Travel In-Market MASTER” and “SPORTS::Sports Enthusiasts.”

###### IP address

Every computer connected to the internet is assigned a unique number known as an internet protocol (IP) address. Since these numbers are usually assigned in country-based blocks, an IP address can often be used to identify the country, and in many cases a more precise location, from which a computer is connecting to the internet.

###### Non-personal information

All forms of user information other than the personal information that you provide to us. This includes, for example, browser type, user device, operating system, IP address, performance statistics, cookie IDs, request-based information, demographic information, unique identifiers, web browsing information, performance information, session information, and log information and other similar data, whether collected by us or received from affiliates or third parties. Please see Section 1 of our Privacy Policy for a more complete description of the non-personal information we collect.

###### Personal information

This is information that you provide to us that personally identifies you, such as your name, email address, billing address and credit card information.

###### Pixel

A pixel, also known as a pixel tag or web beacon, is a small snippet of code embedded in a website. Pixels allow a website to transfer or collect information through a graphic image request. Pixels can be used count site visitations and conversions, gather broad-based user interest data, transmit to and receive information from third parties, deliver, read and write to cookies and for other purposes connected to the provision of advertising, analytics or other services.

###### Server logs

Like most websites, our servers automatically record the page requests made when you visit our sites. These “server logs” typically include your web request, IP address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

###### Unique identifier

A unique identifier is a string of characters that is used to recognize a user’s device, browser or other platform. Unique identifiers may be used in conjunction with or separate from cookies, including on platforms (e.g., certain mobile devices) where cookie technology is not available.

###### User panel

Panel of internet users that agree to anonymous recording of their ad exposure activity as they browse the web and are exposed to video and display advertisements in exchange for free software and services such as browser toolbars, games, and applications that provide information services such as weather, travel, news.

###### Web crawler

A sophisticated bot that renders webpages as a user would in order to analyze the page content and how ads deliver to users on a given webpage.

##### Financial and Health Interest-Based Segments

  * Finance :: Banking
  * Finance :: Business Services
  * Finance :: Credit Cards
  * Finance :: Financial Information & Advice
  * Finance :: Insurance
  * Finance :: Mortgages
  * Finance :: Personal Finance
  * Finance :: Taxes
  * Health :: Dieting
  * Health :: Health Information
  * Health :: Health Insurance
  * Health :: Medical Centers
  * Health :: Pharmaceuticals & Prescription Drugs
